fuel.tv 2009-12-02

# Help Privacy on FUEL.TV – Action Sports Videos, Webcasts, Photos, News, Blogs, & More

## FUEL TV, INC. PRIVACY POLICY (Effective as of January 17, 2008.)

Fuel TV, Inc. (“Fuel TV”) is part of the News America Group, which has adopted a set of Privacy Principles ([http://www.newscorp.com/privacy.html](http://www.newscorp.com/privacy.html)) applicable to all its U.S.-based companies.  Fuel TV has implemented those Principles in this Privacy Policy, which describes how we collect, use and share personally identifiable information (“PII”) we obtain from and about individuals located in the U.S., both online and off-line.   

Fuel TV is a general audience web site, and does not knowingly collect PII from children under 13 years of age.

From time to time Fuel TV may revise this Privacy Policy to reflect industry initiatives or changes in the law, our PII collection and use practices, the features of our Web sites or technology.  If we make revisions that change the way we collect or use your PII, those changes will be posted in this Privacy Policy and the effective date will be noted at the beginning of this Policy.  Therefore, you should review it periodically so that you are up to date on our most current policies and practices.  If Fuel TV materially changes its practices regarding collection or use of your PII, your PII will continue to be governed by the Policy under which it was collected unless you have been provided notice of, and have not objected to, the change.

## COLLECTION:  COLLECTION OF PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION (“PII”) BY FUEL TV

_General_.  Fuel TV **** collects personally identifiable information (“PII” -- that is, information such as your full name, email address, mailing address or telephone number) only in order to create or enhance our relationship with you.  When we collect PII from you it is because you are voluntarily submitting the information to us in order to participate in activities like sweepstakes, contests, games, surveys, forums, subscription registrations, in connection with content or suggestions you submit to us, chats or bulletin boards, or because you want us to furnish you with products, services or information.  We may also obtain PII from reputable third parties.

_Cookies_.   Cookies are small bits of information that the Fuel TV Web sites place on the hard drive of your computer.  Cookies remember information about your activities on our site(s) and enable Fuel TV to make your visits to our site(s) more enjoyable.  For example, cookies can store your password for easy logon to a site you have previously visited, can save your preferences for a personalized home page or can track the items you have placed in your “shopping cart” during a visit to our online store.  Information about your activities on Fuel TV Web sites and other non-personally identifiable information about you may also be used to limit the online ads you encounter to those we believe are consistent with your interests.

Third party advertisements displayed on Fuel TV Web sites may also contain cookies set by Internet advertising companies or advertisers.  Fuel TV does not control these cookies and visitors to our Web site(s) should check the privacy policy of the Internet advertising company or advertiser to see whether and how it uses cookies.  See the “Notice” section below for more information on third party advertisements.

Fuel TV may use cookies and similar tools to relate your use of our Web site(s) to PII obtained from you or a reputable third party.  For example, if you’ve asked us to provide you information about our upcoming products or promotions, cookie and/or click stream data about your activities on Fuel TV Web sites may allow us to limit the materials we provide you to items we think you will find interesting, based on your prior online activities and preferences.  However, if Fuel TV wishes to combine your personal and cookie or click stream information in this manner, we will obtain your express affirmative consent.

You can program your computer to warn you each time a cookie is being sent or to refuse cookies completely.  However, without cookies you may not have access to certain features on Fuel TV’s Web site(s), such as Fuel TV Hook Ups or contests.

## NOTICE:  FUEL TV WILL PROVIDE YOU WITH NOTICE ABOUT ITS PII COLLECTION PRACTICES

When you voluntarily provide PII to Fuel TV, we will make sure you are informed about who is collecting the information, how and why the information is being collected and the types of uses Fuel TV will make of the information.

At the time you provide your PII, Fuel TV will notify you of your options regarding our use of your PII, including whether we will share it with outside companies (See “Choice” below).  This Policy describes the types of other companies that may want to send you information about their products and services and therefore may want to share your personal information, provided you have given Fuel TV permission to do so (See “Use” below).

Sometimes we collect personally identifiable information from consumers in manual format or off-line, such as a post card or subscription form.  Providing detailed notice in those situations often proves impractical, so consumers will instead be provided with a short notice that describes how to obtain the full text of this Policy and other relevant information from us.

Fuel TV’s Web site(s) may be linked to Internet sites operated by other companies.  Some of these third party sites may be co-branded with a Fuel TV logo, even though they are not operated or maintained by Fuel TV (for example, the co-sponsored chat pages, or advertising sponsor pages).  Fuel TV’s Web site(s) also carry advertisements from other companies.  Fuel TV is not responsible for the privacy practices of Web sites operated by third parties that are linked to our site(s) or for the privacy practices of third party or national Internet advertising companies.  Once you’ve left a Fuel TV site via such a link or by clicking on an advertisement, you should check the applicable privacy policy of the third party or advertiser site to determine how they will handle any PII they collect from you.

Fuel TV’s Web site(s) may also be linked to Web sites operated by companies affiliated with Fuel TV (i.e., that are part of the News America Group).  Although all News America Group entities adhere to the group’s Privacy Principles ([http://www.newscorp.com/privacy.html](http://www.newscorp.com/privacy.html)), visitors to those affiliated sites should still refer to their separate privacy policies and practices, which may differ in some respects from this Policy.

Some of the advertisements that appear on Fuel TV’s Web site(s) are delivered to you by national Internet advertising companies such as Doubleclick and 24/7Real Media.  These companies utilize certain technologies to deliver advertisements and marketing messages and to collect anonymous information about your visit to our site(s), including information about the banner ads they display, any cookie they place on your computer and your IP address.  To opt out of information collection by these companies, or to obtain information about the technologies they use or their own privacy policies, please visit:

<http://www.247realmedia.com/privacy.html>

<http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/index.aspx>

<http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>  

##  

## CHOICE:   FUEL TV WILL PROVIDE YOU WITH CHOICES ABOUT THE USE OF YOUR PII

Fuel TV will not use the PII you provide to us for purposes different from the purpose for which it was submitted, or share your PII with third parties that are not affiliated with Fuel TV (i.e., not part of the News America Group), unless we obtain your permission.

**_USE:   _**_FUEL TV’S USE OF PII_

Fuel TV will use your PII provided under this Policy in a manner that is consistent with this Policy.  If Fuel TV obtains PII from a third party, such as a business partner, our use of that information is governed by this Policy.

Fuel TV may share your PII with companies that are affiliated with us, that is, are part of the News America Group of companies.  Provided you have given us permission, Fuel TV may also share your PII with advertisers and business partners that are not affiliated with Fuel TV, but would like to send you information about their products and services.  For example, some of the companies who supply prizes for Fuel TV’s contests may have special offers or promotions that might be of interest to Fuel TV viewers.  However, you will always have the opportunity to instruct us not to share your information with third parties when PII is collected.  Moreover, we will never share your credit card information with third parties except those Fuel TV used to perform tasks (such as order fulfillment and payment processing) required to complete purchases you make through Fuel TV sites.

Fuel TV employees, agents and contractors must have a legitimate business reason to obtain access to your PII.  Fuel TV may share your PII with outside contractors or agents who help us manage our information activities (i.e., sweepstakes administration, order fulfillment, statistical analyses) but they may only use your PII to provide Fuel TV with a specific service and not for any other purpose. 

Fuel TV may also enter into agreements with outside companies that possess the technology that allows Fuel TV to customize the advertising and marketing messages you receive on our Web sites.  Your non-PII and click stream data about your activities on our sites may be shared with these companies so this customization may be accomplished.  These companies will not share your information with any third party or use it for any other purpose.  Anonymous click stream and demographic information may also be shared with Fuel TV’s advertisers and business partners.

There may be instances when Fuel TV may disclose PII without providing you with a choice in order to protect the legal rights of Fuel TV, other companies within the News America Group or their employees, agents and contractors; to protect the safety and security of visitors to our Web sites; to protect against fraud or for risk management purposes; or to comply with the law or legal process.  In addition, if Fuel TV sells all or part of its business or makes a sale or transfer of assets or is otherwise involved in a merger or business transfer, Fuel TV may transfer your PII to a third party as part of that transaction.

**_SECURITY_** _:  FUEL TV PROTECTS THE SECURITY OF PII_

Fuel TV uses reasonable administrative, technical, personnel and physical measures to safeguard PII in its possession against loss, theft and unauthorized use, disclosure or modification.  In addition, Fuel TV uses reasonable methods to make sure that PII is accurate, up-to-date and appropriately complete.

**_ACCESS_** _:   HOW TO ACCESS, CORRECT OR DELETE YOUR PII_

Fuel TV has implemented a procedure for you to access, correct or delete your PII.

To access your PII, send an e-mail with the word “Privacy” in the subject line to [FuelTV.Privacy@fox.com](mailto:FuelTV.Privacy@fox.com?subject=FTVP) or write to the Fuel TV Internet Privacy Officer, at Fox Cable Network Services, LLC Business & Legal Affairs, P.O. Box 900, Beverly Hills, California 90213-0900, requesting a listing of the PII that you have provided.  Fuel TV will respond no later than forty-five (45) business days from receipt of your request with a list of the PII on file.  There may be certain instances when Fuel TV may not be able to provide the PII, such as when access would violate the privacy of another individual, when access is prohibited by law, or when the PII has been lawfully obtained from third party sources.

In the event the PII on file is incorrect, you may correct the PII by sending a written request for correction to the Fuel TV Internet Privacy Officer, at Fox Cable Network Services, LLC Business & Legal Affairs, P.O. Box 900, Beverly Hills, California 90213-0900, including, (1) all of the incorrect PII; (2) the PII that you wish to change; and (3) your signature authorizing such changes.  Fuel TV will then correct the PII in its database and send a written confirmation to you within forty-five (45) business days.

If for any reason you wish to stop all future communications from Fuel TV, you may send an e-mail with the word “Privacy” in the subject line to [FuelTV.Privacy@fox.com](mailto:FuelTV.Privacy@fox.com?subject=FTVP), or write to the Fuel TV Internet Privacy Officer, at Fox Cable Network Services, LLC Business & Legal Affairs, P.O. Box 900, Beverly Hills, California 90213-0900, requesting that your PII be permanently removed form any Fuel TV database.  Fuel TV will send a written confirmation of such removal to you within forty-five (45) business days of receipt of your request.  E-mails sent to [FuelTV.Privacy@fox.com](mailto:FuelTV.Privacy@fox.com?subject=FTVP) for purposes other than communication about PII may not be acknowledged or responded to. ****

**_REMEDIES AND COMPLIANCE_** _:   HOW TO CONTACT FUEL TV ABOUT PRIVACY CONCERNS_

If you have concerns regarding privacy, your use of the Fuel TV Web sites, or the collection and use of PII, you may contact the following Fuel TV representative:

Fuel TV Internet Privacy Officer

Business & Legal Affairs

Fox Cable Network Services, LLC

P.O. Box 900

Beverly Hills, California 90213-0900

Telephone:       (310) 369-1350

You may also request a written response to your concerns, which will be made no later than forty-five (45) business days after you contact Fuel TV.
